<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Petteri Nakamura</title>
    <link>https://nakamura.fi/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Petteri Nakamura</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2023 21:39:03 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://nakamura.fi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Studying Chinese in Taipei for a Month</title>
      <link>https://nakamura.fi/gallery/2023-05-15-rewiew-of-a-month-studying-chinese-in-taipei/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2023 19:28:11 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nakamura.fi/gallery/2023-05-15-rewiew-of-a-month-studying-chinese-in-taipei/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I spent four weeks in Taipei in March to brush up on my Chinese. I had been studying it for about four years before my visit, and had been taking weekly free-talk lessons with online tutors for at least two years. However, the issues I hoped to address with this trip were my habit of reverting to English when I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find a way to express myself in Chinese, and my desire to become more comfortable speaking Mandarin, thus improving my fluency.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Maritime Industry&#39;s Response to Growing Threats Presentation</title>
      <link>https://nakamura.fi/video/2023-04-14-maritime-cybersecurity-turkusec-presentation-2023-04-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2023 16:23:40 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nakamura.fi/video/2023-04-14-maritime-cybersecurity-turkusec-presentation-2023-04-14/</guid>
      <description>I was invited to give a presentation in TurkuSec on the new IMO and IACS requirements on cybersecurity for new ship builds. In this video I explain the significance of the IMO/IACS requirements, how Classification Societies create cybersecurity rules for the industry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Charting a Course to Cybersecurity: The Maritime Industry&#39;s Response to Growing Threats</title>
      <link>https://nakamura.fi/article/2023-02-16-charting-a-course-to-cybersecurity/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2023 19:28:11 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nakamura.fi/article/2023-02-16-charting-a-course-to-cybersecurity/</guid>
      <description>Over the last year I have participated in quite many discussions about cyber security in maritime industry. There is a trend of growing number of cyber attacks in the industry, which have caused lots of disruptions and financial losses for companies and organizations. The shipping industry is also particularly vulnerable to these threats due to the long service lives of onboard systems, growing use of cloud-based solutions by equipment manufacturers and shipowners both in new constructions and also as additions to in-service vessels to enable remote maintenance and collection of data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>D.. What? SPF, DKIM, and DMARC; What Exactly Are They</title>
      <link>https://nakamura.fi/article/2019-01-09-d-what-spf-dkim-and-dmarc-what-exactly-are-they/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2019 19:28:11 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nakamura.fi/article/2019-01-09-d-what-spf-dkim-and-dmarc-what-exactly-are-they/</guid>
      <description>IT is wrought with acronyms and e-mail is no exception. In this post, I will explain how these three help battle spam and other malicious emails, that we all get every day. All of these work behind the scenes and are not visible to the end users of e-mail services, if they don&amp;rsquo;t go looking for them specifically.
Some Background I have often likened e-mail to sending post cards. You write your message on a piece of hard paper, add the recipient address, sign your name, and off it goes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are Finnish Companies Bleeding Edge in the Fight Against Spoofing</title>
      <link>https://nakamura.fi/article/2018-12-11-are-finnish-companies-bleeding-edge-in-the-fight-against-spoofing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 19:28:11 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nakamura.fi/article/2018-12-11-are-finnish-companies-bleeding-edge-in-the-fight-against-spoofing/</guid>
      <description>I took the Friday after the independence day free and apparently I didn&amp;rsquo;t have anything else to do, except to study SPF, DKIM, and DMARC. These are methods for senders to provide authentication for the sent emails to aid spam filters in detecting spoof attempts, with SPF and DKIM being a little bit older and more established, and DMARC being a newer method for communicating policy, building on the foundation of the other two.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
